Trees epitomize stasis.
الأشجار ترمز للركود.
Trees are rooted in the ground in one place
الأشجار متأصلة في الأرض في المكان عينه
for many human generations,
لأجيال متعددة.
but if we shift our perspective
ولكن إذا حولنا وجهة نظرنا
from the trunk to the twigs,
من الجذع الى الاغصان،
trees become very dynamic entities,
ستصبح الاشجار كيانات ديناميكية للغاية،
moving and growing.
تتحرك و تنموا.
And I decided to explore this movement
وقررت استكشاف هذه الحركة
by turning trees into artists.
من خلال تحويل الأشجار إلى فنانين.
I simply tied the end of a paintbrush onto a twig.
لقد قمت ببساطة بوصل نهاية فرشاة الى غصين.
I waited for the wind to come up and held up a canvas,
وانتظرت ان تهب الرياح لترسم لوحة زيتية.
and that produced art.
وقد أنتج هذا فنا.
The piece of art you see on your left
قطعة الفن التي تشاهدها على يسارك
is painted by a western red cedar
تم رسمها بأرز أحمرغربي،
and that on your right by a Douglas fir,
وأما التي على يمينك فبخشب تنوب دوغلاس.
and what I learned was that different species
وما تعلمته هو أن الأنواع المختلفة لها تواقيع مختلفة
have different signatures, like a Picasso versus a Monet.
مثل بيكاسو مقابل مونيه.
But I was also interested in the movement of trees
ولكني كنت أيضا مهتمة بحركة الاشجار
and how this art might let me capture that and quantify it,
وكيف أن هذا الفن قد سمح لي أن ارصده و اقوم بقياسه.
so to measure the distance that a single vine maple tree --
لذلك لقياس المسافة التي قطعتها شجرة كرمة قيقب واحدة --
which produced this painting -- moved in a single year,
التي انتجت هذه اللوحة -- في سنة واحدة ،
I simply measured and summed
أقوم ببساطة بقياس وجمع
each of those lines.
كل هذه الخطوط.
I multiplied them by the number of twigs per branch
ثم ضربت الحاصل في عدد الاغصان لكل فرع
and the number of branches per tree
ثم في عدد الفروع في كل شجرة
and then divided that by the number of minutes per year.
ثم قمت بتقسيم الحاصل على عدد الدقائق في السنة.
And so I was able to calculate
و بذلك تمكنت من حساب
how far a single tree moved in a single year.
مسافة تحرك شجرة واحد في عام واحد
You might have a guess.
بامكانكم التخمين.
The answer is actually 186,540 miles,
الجواب هو 186.540 ميلا،
or seven times around the globe.
أي ما يمثل سبعة أضعاف محيط الأرض.
And so simply by shifting our perspective from a single trunk
فببساطة عن طريق تحويل وجهة نظرنا من جذع واحد
to the many dynamic twigs,
لعدة أغصان ديناميكية،
we are able to see that trees are not simply static entities,
بامكاننا أن نرى أن الأشجار ليست بالكيانات البسيطة الثابتة،
but rather extremely dynamic.
ولكنها ديناميكية للغاية.
And I began to think about ways that
وجعلني هذا أفكر في كيفية
we might consider this lesson of trees,
أخذ العبرة من الأشجار،
to consider other entities that are also static and stuck,
للنظر في الكيانات الأخرى التي هي أيضا ثابتة وجامدة،
but which cry for change and dynamicism,
ولكنها تنادي من أجل التغيير و الديناميكية.
and one of those entities is our prisons.
و احدى الكيانات هذه هي السجون.
Prisons, of course, are where people who break our laws
السجون, بالطبع , هي الأماكن التي يقبع فيها مخالفوا القوانين
are stuck, confined behind bars.
جامدين, مقيدين خلف القضبان.
And our prison system itself is stuck.
و حتى نظام السجن لدينا جامد.
The United States has over 2.3 million
في الولايات المتحدة يقبع أكثر من 2.3 مليون
incarcerated men and women.
امرأة و رجل في السجون.
That number is rising.
و هذا العدد في تزايد.
Of the 100 incarcerated people that are released,
من جملة مائة شخص يتم تسريحهم،
60 will return to prison.
يعود 60 منهم الى السجن.
Funds for education, for training
الأموال المخصصة للتعليم, والتدريب
and for rehabilitation are declining,
و اعادة التأهيل آخذة في الانخفاض.
so this despairing cycle of incarceration continues.
و لا تزال هذه الدورة اليائسة من السجن مستمرة.
I decided to ask whether the lesson
و قررت أن أطرح سؤال ما اذا كانت العبرة
I had learned from trees as artists
التي استنتجتها من الأشجار كفنانين
could be applied to a static institution
يمكن أن تطبق على مؤسسة جامدة
such as our prisons,
كما هو الحال بالنسبة لسجوننا.
and I think the answer is yes.
و اعتقد أن الجواب هو نعم.
In the year 2007,
في سنة 2007،
I started a partnership
بدأت شراكة
with the Washington State Department of Corrections.
مع قسم الإصلاحيات بولاية واشنطن،
Working with four prisons, we began bringing science and scientists,
للعمل مع أربعة سجون، بدأنا بجلب العلم والعلماء،
sustainability and conservation projects
والاستدامة ، ومشاريع صيانة
to four state prisons.
لأربعة سجون في الولاية.
We give science lectures,
قمنا بتقديم محاضرات علمية.
and the men here are choosing to come to our science lectures
و يختار الشخص هنا أن يأتي الى محاضرتنا العلمية
instead of watching television or weightlifting.
عوضا عن مشاهدة التلفاز أو ممارسة رفع الأثقال.
That, I think, is movement.
هذا يمثل، في اعتقادي، تحركا.
We partnered with the Nature Conservancy
قمنا بشراكة مع منظمة الحفاظ على الطبيعة
for inmates at Stafford Creek Correctional Center
لنزلاء مركز إصلاحيات ستافورد كريك
to grow endangered prairie plants
لانماء نباتات البراري المهددة بالانقراض
for restoration of relic prairie areas in Washington state.
لاستعادة ما بقي من مناطق البراري في ولاية واشنطن.
That, I think, is movement.
هذا يمثل، في اعتقادي، تحركا.
We worked with the Washington State Department of Fish and Wildlife
عملنا مع قسم الثروة السمكية و الحياة البرية بولاية واشنطن
to grow endangered frogs -- the Oregon spotted frog --
لتربية ضفادع مهددة بالانقراض، ضفدع أوريغون المرقط،
for later release into protected wetlands.
لاطلاق سراحها لاحقا في أراضي رطبة محمية.
That, I think, is movement.
هذا يمثل، في اعتقادي، تحركا.
And just recently, we've begun to work with
و مؤخرا، شرعنا في العمل مع
those men who are segregated
أولائك الأشخاص المعزولين
in what we call Supermax facilities.
فيما نسميه مرافق سوبرماكس.
They've incurred violent infractions
لقد اقترفوا مخالفات عنيفة
by becoming violent with guards
بأن أصبحوا عنيفين مع الحراس
and with other prisoners.
و مع المساجين الآخرين.
They're kept in bare cells like this
يتم وضعهم في زنازين معزولة مثل هذه
for 23 hours a day.
لمدة 23 ساعة في اليوم.
When they have meetings with their review boards or mental health professionals,
عندما يكون لديهم موعد مع لجنة التقييم أو خبير الصحة العقلية،
they're placed in immobile booths like this.
يتم وضعهم في مقصورة ثابتة مثل هذه.
For one hour a day
لمدة ساعة في اليوم
they're brought to these bleak and bland exercise yards.
يتم جلب هؤلاء الى ساحات التدريب القاتمة و المعزولة هذه.
Although we can't bring trees and prairie plants
و بالرغم من أنه ليس بامكاننا جلب الأشجار و نباتات البراري
and frogs into these environments,
و الضفادع الى هذا المحيط،
we are bringing images of nature
فاننا نكتفي بجلب صور للطبيعة
into these exercise yards,
الى ساحات التدريب هذه،
putting them on the walls, so at least they get contact
لنعلقها على الحيطان، سيكون لديهم على الأقل اتصال
with visual images of nature.
بصري مع صور الطبيعة.
This is Mr. Lopez, who has been in solitary confinement for 18 months,
هذا السيد لوباز، الذي أمضى ثمانية عشر شهرا في السجن للتضامن
and he's providing input on the types of images
وهو بصدد تقديم مداخلة حول نوعيات الصور
that he believes would make him and his fellow inmates
و التي يعتقد أن بامكانها أن تجعله و زملائه النزلاء
more serene, more calm,
أكثر رواقة، أكثر هدوءا،
less apt to violence.
أقل استعدادا للعنف.
And so what we see, I think,
لذا فما نراه، باعتقادي،
is that small, collective movements of change
أن حركات التغيير، الصغيرة و الجماعية هذه
can perhaps move
ربما بامكانها تحريك
an entity such as our own prison system
كيان كامل مثل نظام السجن لدينا
in a direction of hope.
في اتجاه من الأمل.
We know that trees are static entities
نعلم تماما أن الأشجار هي كيانات جامدة
when we look at their trunks.
اذا نظرنا الى جذوعها.
But if trees can create art,
لكن اذا استطاعت الأشجار ابداع الفن،
if they can encircle the globe seven times in one year,
اذا كان بامكانها تطويق كوكب الأرض سبع مرات في سنة واحدة،
if prisoners can grow plants and raise frogs,
اذا كان بامكان المساجين زرع النباتات و تربية الضفادع،
then perhaps there are other static entities
فانه ربما هنالك كيانات أخرى جامدة
that we hold inside ourselves,
نحتفظ بها داخلنا،
like grief, like addictions,
مثل الحزن ، مثل الإدمان ،
like racism,
مثل التمييز العنصري،
that can also change.
والتي بامكانها أيضا أن تتغير.
Thank you very much.
شكرا جزيلا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)